#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

### **Somang Nam**

Toronto, ON Canada Phone: +1-416-897-5008

Email: somang.nam@gmail.com

I am an individual with a passion for many technical fields, especially interested in delivering accessible solutions through data. I am capable of wearing many hats depending on my needs.

As a software engineer, my technical expertise spans many areas of Computer Science, including web application development, data engineering, applications of machine learning (and data science), and game development.

As a scientific researcher, I can design and conduct interdisciplinary user studies in the field of Human-Computer Interaction, Accessibility, and Human Factors. I can perform analysis on both quantitative and qualitative - mixed data and visualize the results to share the findings with both academic and public audiences.

Google Scholar Github LinkedIn Research Gate

# **Degrees**

Ph.D.	Industrial Engineering - Human Factors	University of Toronto	2021
M.Sc.	Computer Science - HCI	Toronto Metropolitan University	2016
H.B.Sc.	Computer Science, Mathematics & Ethnomusicology	University of Toronto	2013

# **Employment history**

I've spent some time as an adjunct lecturer/professor or as a teaching assistant at the university, which are listed <u>separately</u>.

Year (s)	Organization Name, Position Title and specific responsibilities
2022 - current	The Bank of Nova Scotia, Data Engineer Manager
2021 - 2022	National Research Council Canada, Technical Officer-3, development of an open-access platform that calculates quantities related to light and lighting stimuli based on scientific documents (< 25k monthly traffic). React, Node, MathJS, ChartJS
	Spitschan, M., Nam, S., & Veitch, J. A. (2022). luox: Platform for calculating quantities related to light and lighting

2018	PAVO Digital - Toronto Metropolitan University, Software Developer, caption editing software development using ElectronJS and Python
2016	Toronto Metropolitan University, Research Assistant - Data Engineer for a web crawling project about social commerce platform data using Python and Selenium
2013	Universal Music Group (NBC Universal Toronto), Mobile Developer, implemented an Android application prototype for music remix using Youtube API
2012	University of Toronto, Research Assistant - Data Engineer, iSchool and political economics collaborative <u>project</u> . Developed text data mining infrastructure using Python from the Twitter accounts of U.S. congress candidates (~750 accounts). Also collected politically active Twitter users (2.2 million), along with a total of 500,000 tweets over six weeks.

# Projects (personal and team collaboration)

Projects other than school coursework and exclusion of professional experiences. Thesis and research projects are included.

Year	Project
2021	- Worked on a generative art project with multiple artists, using the processingJS and GlitchJS
	- A geolocation-based meta-verse NFT project using Web 3.0 API from Moralis and Ethereum smart contract in Solidity
	<ul> <li>Consulted and designed the software development plan for a Python-web-based voice assistant using a customized voice of the elderly.</li> <li>Trained using Mozilla TTS and Tacotron 2 with Japanese voice clips</li> </ul>
2016-2020	Ph.D. project: Design and development of Closed Captioning quality assessment method using machine learning to replicate Deaf and Hard of Hearing viewers using Active Learning strategy - Multilayer Perceptron implemented under Keras-Tensorflow
2013-2015	M.Sc. project: Design and development of a vibrotactile composition editor implemented using Java. Presented at the Accessibility Innovation Showcase.
2013	Designed and developed a special web browser for the elders with Parkinson's (i.e., shaky hands). Used clustering algorithm to find the hovering finger on a tabletop touch input device (Microsoft Surface Tabletop)
2012	Developed a side-scroller game using Nintendo Wii console (teaser) and presented at the Research In Action & Level Up Showcase. Implemented using Unity3D and Blender.

# Awards and achievements

Exclusion of research funding

2021	Runner up - oral presentations in Data Analytics, AI & Robotics, UTERC 2021 (\$200)
2020-2021	University of Toronto MIE Doctoral Completion Award (\$12,000)
2016-2020	University of Toronto MIE Graduate Fellowship (\$12,500 annually)
2018	IEEE AIKE Best Paper - 2nd place
2016-2021	Graduate Stipendium - issued by Toronto Metropolitan University funding from the Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council (NSERC) Discovery Canada (\$22,000 annually)
2015	Governor General Gold Medal nomination for thesis
2014-2015	Toronto Metropolitan University Graduate Fellowship (\$12,000 annually)
2013-2015	Graduate Stipendium - issued by Toronto Metropolitan University funding from the Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council (SSHRC) and GRAND Canada (\$18,000 annually)
2013-2014	Toronto Metropolitan University Graduate Award (\$8,000)
2013-2016	Google Code Jam (qualified for three consecutive years, Round 1 for 2013 entry top 20%)
2006	<ul> <li>Medalist, FIRST (For Inspiration and Recognition of Science and Technology)</li> <li>Vex Robotics official tournament</li> <li>1st (2006) and 2nd (2005) place in Civil Canada Arm, McMaster Engineering &amp; Science Olympics</li> </ul>

# Peer-reviewed publications & presentations

Life-Time Summary	
Refereed Journal Articles	3
Refereed Conference Proceedings (presentations)	3 (6)
Paper Reviews	2

#### Selected publications

- Spitschan, M., Mead, J., Roos, C., Lowis, C., Griffiths, B., Mucur, P., Herf, M., Nam, S., & Veitch, J. A. (2022). luox: novel validated open-access and open-source web platform for calculating and sharing physiologically relevant quantities for light and lighting. Wellcome Open Res, 6, 69. doi:10.12688/wellcomeopenres.16595.3
- Nam, S., Fels, D., & Chignell, M. Toward a Subjective Assessment System for Closed Captioning Quality. SMPTE Motion Imaging Journal, 130(3), 35-44, White Plains, NY (2021)
- Nam, S., Fels, D. I., & Chignell, M. H. Modeling Closed Captioning Subjective Quality
  Assessment by Deaf and Hard of Hearing Viewers. IEEE Transactions on Computational Social
  Systems (SCIE, IF = 5.36). (2020)
- Nam, S. Designing a Subjective Assessment System for the Quality of Closed Captioning Using Artificial Intelligence. Broadcast Engineering and Information Technology Conference, Washington, USA (2020)

- Nam, S., & Fels, D. Simulation of Subjective Closed Captioning Quality Assessment Using Prediction Models. International Journal of Semantic Computing (ESCI, IF=1.03), 13(01), 45-65. (2019)
- Nam, S., & Fels, D. Assessing closed captioning quality using a multilayer perceptron. In 2018
  IEEE First International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Knowledge Engineering (AIKE)
  (pp. 9-16). IEEE. (2018)
- Nam, S., & Fels, D. Design and evaluation of an authoring tool and notation system for vibrotactile composition. International Conference on Universal Access in Human-Computer Interaction (pp. 43-53). Springer, Cham. (2016)

#### **Presentations**

- luox An open-source, open-access web platform implementing international standards for the quantification of light, Lightning Talks track, FOSDEM 2022 - Free and Open-source Software Developers' European Meeting, Brussels, Belgium (2022)
- Towards an automatic caption quality assessment model reflecting the subjective views of Deaf, and Hard of Hearing audiences, Oral Presentations in Data Analytics, Al & Robotics, UTERC 2021, Toronto, Canada (2021)
- Towards designing a subjective assessment method for the quality of Closed Captioning using deep neural networks. Internal webinar for OVPECI, Toronto Metropolitan University, Canada (2020)
- Designing a Subjective Assessment System for the Quality of Closed Captioning Using Artificial Intelligence. NAB Show, Las Vegas, USA (2020)
- Nam, S. and Fels, D. Assessing closed captioning quality using a multilayer perceptron. IEEE Artificial Intelligence and Knowledge Engineering, Laguna Hills, California, USA (2018)
- Design and Evaluation of an Authoring Tool and Notation System for Vibrotactile Composition.
   Human-Computer Interaction International 2016, Toronto, Canada (2016)

#### **Reviews**

- IEEE Transactions on Computational Social Systems (TCSS), 2022
- Graphics Interface (GI 22), 2022
- The Special Interest Group on Computer-Human Interaction (ACM-SIGCHI), 2018
- International Conference on Computers Helping People with Special Needs (ICCHP), 2014

#### Memberships

Member of IEEE Computer Society Technical Committee on Semantic Computing (TCSC): No.96579108

# Teaching experience

List of courses that I have participated in as a sessional lecturer or as a (lead) Teaching Assistant (TA). I provided lectures, created course outlines, and designed and held practical tutorials, assignments, projects, and exams.

Adjunct Professor / Lecturer		
2022	CPS613/CP8205 Human-Computer Interaction, Toronto Metropolitan University	
2019	(C)ITM350 Concepts of e-Business, Toronto Metropolitan University	
Lead TA / Substitute Lecturer		
2018	ITM350 Concepts of e-Business, Toronto Metropolitan University	
	MIE344 Ergonomic Design of Information Systems, University of Toronto	
2017 - 2018	MIE253 Data modelling, MS Access, MySQL for OLAP with Java, University of Toronto	
2016 - 2017	ITM780 Web design and Management, JavaScript and HTML5, Toronto Metropolitan University	
2015	ITM445 Multimedia in Business, Adobe Suites, Toronto Metropolitan University	
TA		
2016	CPS209 Computer Science: Object-Oriented Programming, C++, Toronto Metropolitan University	
2015	CPS506 Comparative programming languages, Haskell and Rust, Toronto Metropolitan University	
2014 - 2015	CPS305 Data Structure, Java, Toronto Metropolitan University	
2013 - 2014	CPS125 Digital Computation and Programming, Matlab, Toronto Metropolitan University	
2013	CPS105 Intro to Computer Science, Java, Toronto Metropolitan University	
	CPS118 Introductory Programming for Scientist, C++, Toronto Metropolitan University	

### Course development

- CPS613/CP8205, Human-Computer Interaction, created a full course material, assignments, and project. (2022)
- ITM350, Concepts of e-Business, assisted Professor Deborah Fels in redesigning the course and assignments. (2018)
- ITM780, Web Design and Management, assisted Professor Deborah Fels in redesigning the course and assignments. (2017)

# Research grants

 Broadcasting Accessibility Fund, To develop an automated quality assessment system for Closed Captioning, \$92,161 (2020)